<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
/**
 * @author Aitoc Team
 * @copyright Copyright (c) 2020 Aitoc (https://www.aitoc.com)
 * @package Aitoc_FollowUpEmailsEnt
 */
-->
<!--
  ~ Copyright © 2019 Aitoc. All rights reserved.
  -->
<config xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="urn:magento:module:Aitoc_FollowUpEmails:etc/event_attributes.xsd">
    <events>

        <event>
            <code>abandoned_cart</code>
            <name>Abandoned Cart</name>
            <short_description><![CDATA[Return to Checkout customers who have put something into their cart and then left your site. Craft creative email campaigns to increase CTR of your letters. Decide after what time the cart is considered abandoned and automate Return To Cart emails. Embed discounts into your Return To Cart emails to entice users to make a purchase.]]></short_description>
            <description><![CDATA[<h4>TARGET AUDIENCE</h4><p>Customers who placed items into their cart but never proceeded to Checkout. They might need just a little nudge or a neat discount to complete their purchase in your store. Some customers are just browsing one website after another in a long search for the product of their dreams. Convince them your product is the best choice.</p><h4>TRIGGER</h4><p>A cart has been created but not opened for a certain amount of time.<p><h4>WHEN TO SEND</h4><p>It’s hard to predict the optimal timing of each email. It depends a lot on the type of customers you usually deal with, the average time between the research and the decision to actually buy the product. Take a look at how long an average customer spends on your website before they buy something. Note how many pages and products they view, what questions they ask (if any).</p><p>This information will offer you general understanding of what their buyer’s journey is. Make your email intervals smaller for less expensive and more emotions-driven products and a bit larger for significant purchases where users don’t make decisions rashly.</p><br><h4>Suggested intervals:</h4><ul><li><b>Email #1:</b> Send 1 hour after someone abandons your shopping cart without returning to complete the purchase</li><li><b>Email #2:</b> Send 12-24 hours after the first email, if the prospect has still not made a purchase</li><li><b>Email #3:</b> Send 24-48 hours after email #2, if the prospect has still not made a purchase</li><ul/><h4>CAMPAIGN GOALS</h4><ul><li>Encourage purchases</li><li>Get your customers back to the store</li><li>Demonstrate good customer service</li></ul><h4>BEST PRACTICES</h4><ul><li>Let users know that supply is low</li><li>Add an authentic, positive user review</li><li>Offer discounts to boost sales</li><li>Include similar items as a cross-sell promotion</li></ul>]]></description>
        </event>

        <event>
            <code>abandoned_order</code>
            <name>Abandoned Order</name>
            <short_description><![CDATA[Use Abandoned Orders to return those customers to the store who have placed an order but never got around to paying for it. Send out emails with custom discounts to gain customer interest and entice them to finish their purchase in your store. Set a chain of emails with reminders of their pending order status. Autologin users on the site when they click the link in the email.]]></short_description>
            <description><![CDATA[<h4>TARGET AUDIENCE</h4><p>Customers who proceeded to Checkout but never finished their order. They’ve filled in all the necessary contact details, but something went wrong. Maybe the shipping cost was too high. Maybe they decided to browse some more in the last minute. Or maybe they were suddenly interrupted and forgot about their order after a while. Give them an opportunity to complete their shopping and get a new paying customer.</p><h4>TRIGGER</h4><p>An order hasn’t been paid for during a predefined period of time.<p><h4>WHEN TO SEND</h4><p>Being in the right place in the right time makes all the difference in the world. In our case – sending an email with the right offer to the customer. The trick is to find out when is the right time to make this offer.</p><p>Practise and learn when is the best time to email your customers. Don’t be afraid to experiment with different time intervals and wordings. Create and send out a chain of letters, maybe offering progressively larger incentives to convince even the most skeptical buyers.</p><p>Different time intervals will work for different businesses. But we have a few general suggestions.</p><br><h4>Suggested intervals:</h4><ul><li><b>Email #1:</b> Send 1 hour after someone abandons your order placement process without returning to complete the purchase</li><li><b>Email #2:</b> Send 12-24 hours after the first email, if the prospect has still not made a purchase</li><li><b>Email #3:</b> Send 24-48 hours after email #2, if the prospect has still not made a purchase</li><ul/><h4>CAMPAIGN GOALS</h4><ul><li>Encourage more purchases</li><li>Get your customers back to the store</li><li>Demonstrate good customer service</li><li>Increase the recipient’s average order value (AOV) by cross- or up-selling</li></ul><h4>BEST PRACTICES</h4><ul><li>Test if something on the checkout page prevents visitors from finishing the order, like additional costs or taxes</li><li>Include key features or benefits (such as next-day delivery) that might help you get the purchase over the line</li><li>Check shipping pricing to make sure that high shipping rates don’t turn your customers off</li><li>Offer support service so your customers always know where to direct their questions</li></ul>]]></description>
        </event>

        <event>
            <code>welcome_email</code>
            <name>Welcome Email</name>
            <short_description><![CDATA[Instead of sending out a bland welcome email that will be deleted the moment it lands in the user’s inbox, use this opportunity to communicate with your customer for the first time. Focus on brand presentation and company image. Include video links and other materials about your company and its vision in the email.]]></short_description>
            <description><![CDATA[<h4>TARGET AUDIENCE</h4><p>New subscribers (signed-up only and subscribed via a purchase).</p><h4>TRIGGER</h4><p>New customer registration event.<p><h4>WHEN TO SEND</h4><p>Welcome email is a great opportunity to open a new channel of communication with your customers. This is likely the first email your brand new customer will get from you. Making the right decision when and what will be inside is crucial for success. Obviously, you will send the very first welcome email right after the registration.</p><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><h4>Suggested intervals:</h4><ul><li><b>Email #1:</b> Send immediately after registration</li><ul/><h4>CAMPAIGN GOALS</h4><ul><li>Set subscriber expectations</li><li>Encourage subscribers to connect on social channels</li><li>Make a strong first impression</li><li>Get subscribers back to your store</li><li>Turn leads into first-time buyers</li><li>Turn first-time buyers into repeat customers</li></ul><h4>BEST PRACTICES</h4><ul><li>Use either dynamic content or campaign segmentation to create different experiences for those who (a) are already familiar with your brand and have made a purchase and (b) know nothing about your brand and are yet to make a purchase</li><li>Offer a discount, giveaway or free trial as an incentive to subscribe to company emails</li><li>Include CTAs to follow you on social media or to check out your blog</li><li>Avoid spam trigger words like Affordable, Apply now, Call free/now, etc</li><li>You can experiment with a welcome email series which sends multiple messages and introduces all the main ideas one by one</li></ul>]]></description>
        </event>

        <event>
            <code>review_booster</code>
            <name>Product Reviews &amp; Ratings</name>
            <short_description><![CDATA[Reviews are a powerful tool to build trust and boost sales of your products. They are great when you want to create original and Google-trusted content with zero effort. In addition, Google uses this content within its Rich Snippets section on the search results page. Let users add photos to their reviews, outline pros and cons, vote on other reviews and report abusive content – all within a single comprehensive extension that focuses on reviews-driven SEO and sales growth.]]></short_description>
            <description><![CDATA[<h4>TARGET AUDIENCE</h4><p>Customers who have made a purchase and can share their experience using the product.</p><h4>TRIGGER</h4><p>Users who have purchased a product will receive an email after some time where they will be asked to leave a review.</p><h4>WHEN TO SEND</h4><p>The optimal time to ask for a product review is approximately a third into its lifetime. So ask for a review in 2-3 days after the product is delivered for short-lived products that are quick to be consumed and then discarded. Wait asking for feedback of more long-lasting things until you are sure the customer has formed a comprehensive and all-round opinion about their experience.</p><p>The trick is to choose the exact time when the customer is still happy about their purchase and cares enough to share their experience with everyone else.</p><br><h4>There’s no silver bullet for every product out there, but we suggest the following interval:</h4><ul><li><b>Email #1:</b> Send 2-7 days after the item is delivered. Ask for feedback and review, offer help.</li><ul/><h4>CAMPAIGN GOALS</h4><ul><li>Collect feedback about your products</li><li>Boost the number of reviews</li><li>Make products more appealing due to high number of user reviews</li></ul><h4>BEST PRACTICES</h4><ul><li>Offer a discount to convince your customers to write more reviews</li><li>Try to answer all reviews. Your users will appreciate even the modest "Thank you for your review!" line</li><li>Always make sure you account for shipping time before sending a review request</li></ul>]]></description>
        </event>

        <event>
            <code>user_birthday</code>
            <name>User Birthday</name>
            <short_description><![CDATA[Use your customers’ birthday as a great opportunity to show you care about them, and also as a chance to offer interesting deals or discounts for your registered users. Small gestures like that, if done right, will show that you care and will quickly pay off.]]></short_description>
            <description><![CDATA[<h4>TARGET AUDIENCE</h4><p>Customers who have a birthday coming up.<p><h4>TRIGGER</h4><p>Registered customer birthday.<p><h4>WHEN TO SEND</h4><p>Offer your customers exclusive and time-limited deals tied closely to their birthday. Whether you send the email in advance or right on the day of the big event, there’s an awesome opportunity to boost sales with automated custom discounts and promotions.</p><p>When you first try out the extension, we suggest you experiment with different templates and intervals for a bit to get a better understanding about the optimal shopping window for your customers and what interests them most.</p><br><h4>Suggested intervals:</h4><ul><li><b>Email #1:</b> Send 3-10 days before the birthday</li><li><b>Email #2:</b> Send on the day of the event</li><ul/><h4>CAMPAIGN GOALS</h4><ul><li>Build relationship with the customer</li><li>Boost sales with outstanding customer care</li></ul><h4>BEST PRACTICES</h4><ul><li>Find out the best time window when your emails generate the most clicks and sales</li><li>Experiment with different content formats to see what offers and content interest your customers most</li></ul>]]></description>
        </event>

        <event>
            <code>we_miss_you</code>
            <name>We miss you</name>
            <short_description><![CDATA[We Miss You is a cornerstone extension that will help you return registered customers to the store, email them free gift offers and promotions based on how long these customers haven’t logged into your store. It is designed to re-engage customers who have lapsed or who are at risk of lapsing.]]></short_description>
            <description><![CDATA[<h4>TARGET AUDIENCE</h4><p>Customers who have been inactive for a while.<p><h4>TRIGGER</h4><p>A customer that hasn’t logged in for a predefined number of days.<p><h4>WHEN TO SEND</h4><p>Your customers might have liked your store, but they are overloaded with information every day and can easily forget which store they bought from. Remind the users about your existence in an elegant and unobtrusive way. Exact intervals will depend greatly on the typical behavior of your customers and product specifics. Whether your users make regular purchases or not, how often they usually do shopping, whether they are loyal to the brand or only interested in deals and discounts. All this will determine your email strategy.</p><br><h4>Suggested intervals:</h4><ul><li><b>Email #1:</b> Send an email after 25 days the user last logged in into your store. Offer a time-restricted deal that creates a sense of urgency</li><li><b>Email #2:</b> If the first email was unsuccessful, come up with something new in 90 days</li><ul/><h4>CAMPAIGN GOALS</h4><ul><li>Re-activate customers that have lapsed</li><li>Re-engage those at risk of lapsing</li></ul><h4>BEST PRACTICES</h4><ul><li>Display too-good-to-pass-up offer (a free product, a discount, or a chance to win something)</li><li>Add questions or surveys to engage the audience</li><li>Remind the recipient of the key benefits of shopping with your brand</li></ul>]]></description>
        </event>

        <event>
            <code>post_purchase_email</code>
            <name>Post Purchase Email</name>
            <short_description><![CDATA[Post-purchase emails can include a brief note where you thank the customer for the purchase. You can also include links to helpful customer support channels, user manual PDF, offer discount for the next purchase and list most interesting products they might like right in the letter.]]></short_description>
            <description><![CDATA[<h4>TARGET AUDIENCE</h4><p>Customers who made a purchase.<p><h4>TRIGGER</h4><p>An order that has been paid for and processed.<p><h4>WHEN TO SEND</h4><p>As a business your goal is not to view the purchase as the end result of your interaction with the customer. Post-purchase emails will help you build a lasting relationship with your shoppers and turn one-time customers into repeat customers. Plan your email campaigns with this goal in mind.</p><p>We suggest that you send your first post-purchase email asking the customer to leave a review about the product or take a quick survey about their experience with your store. The exact interval here depends on how much time you think your customer will need to form an opinion. After 7-14 days you could send a new offer together with a coupon or another kind of promotion.</p><br><h4>Suggested intervals:</h4><ul><li><b>Email #1:</b> Send before or when the item is delivered. Ask if everything is great. Offer learning materials, instructions, manuals, FAQs</li><li><b>Email #2:</b> Send a new offer in 12-14 days</li><ul/><h4>CAMPAIGN GOALS</h4><ul><li>Demonstrate you’re there for the customer if something goes wrong</li><li>Plant the seeds for the next purchase</li></ul><h4>BEST PRACTICES</h4><ul><li>Thank customers for their purchase</li><li>Show the ways to receive support service if needed</li><li>At the bottom of the email, display a few products that are similar to the ones purchased, or products that go well with them</li><li>Include information like product care, product use cases, or a product FAQ</li></ul>]]></description>
        </event>

        <event>
            <code>custom_order_status_change</code>
            <name>Custom Order Status Change</name>
            <short_description><![CDATA[This event helps you adapt Magento to your unique business workflows. Custom Order Status Change lets you assign multiple emails to specific order statuses, notify different people both inside and outside of Magento store about the order progress, and speed up order completion thanks to eliminating the communication steps that previously were performed manually.<br><br><b>Example:</b> A company with a complex customized picking and packing process will benefit the most from this solution. Individual team members will be able to receive email alerts exactly when they need to do something with the order. This speeds up order processing and allows to track at which stage an order might get stuck longer than usual.]]></short_description>
            <description><![CDATA[<h4>TARGET AUDIENCE</h4><p>Users who supervise detailed order progress throughout the system. Company employees who need to track custom order statuses more closely.<p><h4>TRIGGER</h4><p>The system will check if an email has to be sent on each order status change.<p><h4>WHEN TO SEND</h4><p>Email alerts are of course sent as soon as possible to speed up order processing.</p><br><br><br><br><br><br><h4>Suggested intervals:</h4><ul><li><b>Email #1:</b> Send an email immediately when the order changes its status. Explain why the user receives this particular email and what the custom status means</li><ul/><h4>CAMPAIGN GOALS</h4><ul><li>Offer key support contacts in case of issues</li><li>Adapt Magento order statuses to your business process</li><li>Make order processing more efficient with automated email alerts</li></ul><h4>BEST PRACTICES</h4><ul><li>Streamline notifications about custom order status changes to save time on order processing</li><li>Lower the number of emails in the system only sending email updates to employees that need them at the moment</li><li>Let users interested in order tracking a flexible way to monitor order completion progress</li></ul>]]></description>
        </event>

    </events>
</config>
